听译：阿夙  未未  阿汤  阿莫  Kelly  小新 王某人
校对：大玄
时间轴/后期：阿汤
【本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁商用，请于下载后24小时内删除】
【如果喜爱本片，希望大家去影院再刷一遍】
【支持正版么么哒~】
【随便字幕组】不随便出品
Life was given to us a billion years ago.
我们的生命起源于十亿年前
What've we done with it?
但我们用生命干了什么？
Lucy?
Lucy？
It is an eaiest pie. In an hour all done in busted.
这简直小菜一碟，一个小时之内就都搞定了
Then why don't you do it yourself?
既然如此你为什么不自己去呢？
The last thing the guy expecting is a total ten turning up with delivery of the case.
那个人最期待的是像你这样的美女送这个箱子
You'll blow his mind, come on.
你会让他眼前一亮的，拜托了
- What's in it? - Sweet heart.
- 这里面装了什么？ - 亲爱的
Don't get a paranoid on me, right? You trust me, don't you?
别胡思乱想了，你难道不相信我吗？
Richard, I really do like you.
Richard 我确实很喜欢你
But I have to take care of myself right now. I gotta...
但是现在我要顾上自己，我得……
I don't know, gotta concentrate on so many things.
我也不知道，得要专心干点事了
嘿，你要干什么？
Hey! What are you doing?
I'm going home because I have an exam on Monday!
我要回家了，周一我还有一个测验
I have to shower, and I have to study, OK?
我要去洗个澡，然后学习，懂了吗？
you know what, the other day I was in this museum.
你知道吗，有一天我去了这个博物馆
- And you know what I found out? - What?
- 你知道我发现了什么吗？ - 什么？
The first civil woman was named 'Lucy'.
第一个文明时期的女人就叫Lucy
- That's supposed to mean what you feel about her? - Yeah. No.
- 你觉得这就让我觉得好受些？ - 是的，其实没有
- I'll call you, OK? - OK, OK! OK.
- 我会给你打电话的，好吗？ - 好吧，好吧
I'll be honest with you. I can't deliver the case myself. I had out the phone out of that guy.
我坦白告诉你，我不能亲自送这个箱子，我和那人通过电话
It's nothing major, but if it's you, problem solved.
这不是什么大问题，但如果是你去送，问题就解决了
You walk in there. You go up to the reception.
你只要走进去，走到前台
You ask to meet Mr. Jang to come down.
你说要见张先生
He comes down. He takes the case.
他会下来拿箱子
You flash your prettiest smile, and bangs!
你再给他最甜美的微笑，一切就都搞定了
Look, you can even see the reception from here, come on!
看，你从这儿就能看到前台了，拜托了
- What is in the case? - I don't know, it's... some paperwork.
- 箱子里有什么？ - 我不知道，大概是……一些文件吧
- Yeah? See it then. - It's locked, and no one but Mr. Jang has the code..
- 真的？那就打开看看。 - 它锁上了，只有张先生知道密码
I am just the delivery boy.
我只是一个负责送货的
- Do you get paid to do this? - Yeah, kinda of.
- 做这个他们付你钱了吗？ - 有啊，给了点
Like, how much?
有……多少？
- OK, we're negotiating now, or... - No, no! How much you get paid, I wanna know, how much?
- 好吧，我们现在是在讨价还价了，还是…… - 不，不，你赚了多少钱。我想知道，有多少？
- $1,000. - You got paid $1000 for delivering paperwork, really?
- 1000美金 - 你送文件就赚了了1000美金，真的假的？
I don't know, it takes me 10 minutes and they pay me a grand, and the rest is not my business.
我不知道，我花个十分钟就能赚1000美金，其余的就不关我事
- Well, it's not my business neither, I'm telling you now. - Listen!
- 行，那我告诉你这也不关我的事。 -听着！
- What? - It's been a double minute, uhu? That's 500 for you and 500 for me.
- 怎么了？ - 我们对半分，恩？给你500，给我500
- Richard, I'll call you. - Listen, it's third time this week I'm showing up in the same hotel with the same cowboy hat.
- Richard，我会给你打电话的。 - 听着，这是这周第三次我带着同样的牛仔帽在这个酒店出现了
Problem solved. Go, go, I'll wait for you, go.
现在问题解决了。去吧，我会等你的，快去
Lucy, honey, I've done this a dozen times, it's paperwork.
Lucy，亲爱的，我做过好多次了，这就是些文件
It's probably just a design script they can copy with.
可能就是一些他们想模仿的设计手稿
That's how it works in this country.
这种事这个国家常有
Even my stetson was made here, look!
就连我的牛仔帽都是这里制造的，你看
Stetson on the label, made in Taiwan.
标签上写着，台湾制造
So long, cowboy was a fakester.
再见了，谎话连篇的牛仔
- Baby please! - Richard, I gotta go ...
- 宝贝，拜托了！ - Richard，我真的得走了
- What the hell are you doing? -I'm sorry.
- 你特么在做什么？ - 我很抱歉
What the hell are you do...
你他妈的到底在做什么
I'm so sorry, I really need your help.
我十分抱歉，我真的需要你的帮助
- Stop this, stop it! Take this off me right now! - I can't.
- 住手，住手，现在就把这个给我打开！  - 我不能打开
- All you have to do is going to the hotel and ask him to meet at the reception.  - No, take it off me right now!
- 你所要做的只是走进这家酒店，然后约他在柜台碰面就可以了。 - 不，把它给我打开！
I've been so sorry, I really have no choice as soon you going, as soon you'll be back on.
我非常抱歉，我真的没有办法，你越早把这送进去，你就能越早出来
I can't believe you do this to me.
我不敢相信你居然会这么对我
I'll be right here, you have my word.
我就在这里等你，我保证
Your word is worth shit!
你的保证算个屁
That's worth 500 bucks of front.
算五百块，就在你眼前
You're an asshole.
你这个混蛋
And you're wonderful!
但你最棒了
Miss, may I help you?
小姐，我能帮你什么吗？
Uh,yes.
呃，是的
I'm here for...errr...Mr. Jang.
我到这是来找，呃，张先生的
- Take this off me right now! - I can't. Jane is the one who has the key.
- 现在给我打开！ - 我做不到，只有张先生才有钥匙
Yes.
好的
Who should I say is here?
我应该说找他的人是谁？
Richard!
Uh, R...Richard sent me.
呃 R……Richard派我来的
What's your name?
你叫什么名字？
No, Richard!
不是我，就是Richard
Richard's...he's just looking for a place to park.
Richard在……他在找停车位
Mr. Jang still wants to know your name.
张先生还是想知道你的名字
- Lucy. - Lucy what？
Lucy - Lucy什么？
- L...just Lucy! If he...if he could be quick, cuz I've... I've got some...do.
就是……就是Lucy！他能不能……能不能快一些，因为我……我还有……
- Just a second wait, I will translate.
请稍等，等我翻译一下
Mr. Jang is on his way. Stay right here.
张先生在来的路上，你就在这里等吧
Can...can I sit?
我……我能坐下吗？
Mr. Jang said you need to stay right here.
张先生说你需要在这里等
I think it's better if you stay right here.
我觉得你最好就待在这里
Excuse me,  Regent Hotel.
不好意思，这里是晶华酒店
No!
不！
不要！
No, Wait!
不，等等！
No!
不要！
Please, please, please!
求求你们！求求你们了！
Please! I don't know anything!
拜托！我什么都不知道！
I don't know anything, please!
我真的什么都不知道！求求你们了！
please!
拜托你们！
please! What?
求你了！什么？
please!
不要！
Please!
求求你们了！
Do you speak English?
你会说英语吗？
(Spanish)
你会说西班牙语吗？
It's just been a terrible mistake
这一切都搞错了
I am just supposed to deliver this case
我本来只是负责运送这个箱子的
If you lost the key,you don't have to chop off my hand, you can just cut the chain ,ok?
你如果找不到箱子的钥匙了，能别砍我的手
要是想开箱子把铁链砍断就可以，好吗？
Please
求你了
I am begging you,please
我求求你了
No...no...no
不要不要
Please...please
求你们了
Hello,Miss,I speak English,I translate for Mr.Jang
小姐你好,我会说英语，我替张先生翻译
Please tell him that I haven't done anything
请你告诉他，我什么都没干
I don't know anything,it's all just be a mistake,ok?
我也什么都不知道，这一切都是个误会，可以吗？
Please,please tell him that—Yes,ok,ok,ok
请你告诉他这些 —好的，我会的
-Mr.Jang wants to know what's in the case —I don't know what's in the case!
张先生想知道箱子里都是些什么 —我不知道箱子里有什么！
Do you speak English or don't you speak English?
你到底会不会英语？
Yes,I do.I studied one year in a international high school in New York
我当然会，我在纽约的国际高中学习过一年
Ok
那好
Richard gave me the case to give to you,that's all I know.Ok,please tell him that.
Richard给了我箱子让我转交给你，我知道的就这么多，请转告他这些
He gave me a paper with numbers written on it.I don't know what is this?
他给了我一张写了数字的纸，我不知道这是什么
It's the code to open the case
这是开箱子的密码
-What's really in here?—Nothing dangerous
这箱子里到底有什么? —不会有危险的
So why won't you open it themsleves?
那他们为什么不自己打开箱子?
-He doesn't trust Mr.Richard—I don't trust Richard either. I only dated him for a week
-他不信任Richard -我也不相信Richard啊，我才和他约会了一个星期啊
-Ok,ok,ok—Mr.Jang insist that you open the case
-好好，我来开 -张先生坚持要你打开这个箱子
Please god help me
老天，救救我吧
He wants you to hurry up,Mr Jang has other things to do.
张先生希望你动作快点，他还有其他的事要忙
Can you describe the content of the case?
你能说清箱子里有什么吗？
It's four plastic pouches filled with blue powder,maybe purple powder?I don't know,looks gross
这有四个塑料袋，袋子里装满了蓝色的粉末，或许是紫色的粉末？
我不确定，看起来挺恶心的
-Mr.Jang wants to offer you a job—A job?
-张先生打算给你份工作 -一份工作?
I don' t want a job!
我不想要这个工作!
If life starts approximately a billion years ago，
如果生命大约于10亿年前出现
we won't have to wait 400,000 years to see the  aberration of first nerve cells.
我们也就不必要等了四十万年，第一个神经细胞才变异
This is where life as we know it begins.
这也就是我们所知晓的生命开始的时候
Brain and formation is only a few milligrams.
大脑及其构成最初只有几毫克重
It's not possible to determine for any sign of intelligence yet.
这根本不可能判定它是否存在形成智慧的迹象
It asks more as a reflex.
更多的只是一种反射
One neuron,you are alive.
有一个神经元，你被赋予了生命
Two neurons,you're moving
有两个神经元，你就能动起来了
And with the movement,interesting things began to happen
而伴随着运动，有趣的事就开始发生了
Animal life on earth goes back millions of years.
动物在地球上的存在的历史可以追随到数百万年前
Yet most species only use 3-5% of their cerebra capacity.
可大多数物种只使用了它们脑容量的3-5%
But it is until we reach the human being at the top of the animal chain.
直到人类作为动物链顶端的生物出现
That we finally see our species use more cerebra capacity.
我们才终于有了一个能够使用更多脑容量的物种
10% may not seem like much,but a lot when look at what we done with it.
10%可能听着不是很多
但是看着我们用它干了什么你就知道这很了不起了
Now let's discuss a special case.
现在让我们来谈谈一个特殊的例子
The only living being that uses its brain
唯一一个能够在使用大脑这方面
better than us
超越我们的物种
The dolphin
海豚
It is estimated that this incredible animal
据估计，这种非同凡响的动物
uses up to 20% of their cerebra capacity
至多使用到了它们脑容量的20%
And particular,this allows it to have an echolocation system
然后很特殊地，这使得它们自身具备了回声定位系统
that is more efficient than any sonar invented by mankind.
其高效性完全超越了人类所发明的各种声呐设备
But the dolphin didn't invent the sonar,it developed it naturally.
但是海豚并没有发明声呐，这是其自身形成的
And this is the crucial part of our philosophical reflection we have today.
这就是我们今天哲学思考的关键部分
Can we therefore conclude that
我们能否因此定论
humans are concerned more with having
人类更加在意是否拥有
Than being
而非自我存在
Lucy
what have you do to my stomach?
你在我的腹部上干了什么？
nothing,just a little horizontal slit,it's very well done
只是一个水平小切口，手术很成功……
and you'll find it within a month it's going promptly invisible.
你会发现几个月内疤痕就会很快消失
-you'll be very sure to return to the beach next summer. -i don't care about the scar.
-明年夏天你就能回到沙滩了 -我不在乎疤痕
is it...is it worry we'll take your organ?
你是……你是怕我们拿掉你的器官吗？
Rest assured, we didn't hurt your organism and we nearly sliped a little package into your little tummy.
放心，我们没动你的器官，只是把一小袋东西放到你的肚子里
-it's a...it's a new drug,the kids in Europe are gonna love it,believe me. -what is it?
-那是……那是种新药, 相信我，欧洲的小屁孩们都会爱上的 -那是什么 ？
well,the scientific term is CPH4.
它的科学术语叫CPH4.
cause it's not very sexy for sales,so we are still working on something with a bit more pop.
因为这名字太蠢了，卖不掉，所以我们还在想个带点流行元素的名字
-any suggestions? -uh... -aw,excuse me.
-你有什么建议吗？ -这…… -啊，稍等片刻
welcome,welcome,come on in.lovely boots.
欢迎，欢迎，请进。这靴子真帅。
splendid!splendid!
真棒！真棒！
marvelous,lovely,lovely
简直棒啊，太棒了太棒了！
-how are you?-very good,i tell.
-你好吗? -我很好
right,um...first of all,many thanks for taking part in this enterprise.
首先，万分感谢你们参与这项计划。
which i'm sure it'll go on fluently
我确信这项计划将顺利进行。
these lovely passport and tickets will enable you return home in the next 24 hours.
这些可爱的护照和机票能让你们在接下来的24小时里回到家中
Now, upon arrival,you will be taken in hand by our people,so listen,we might recover on merchandise
抵达目的地后，你们会被我们的人所接管，他们拿回我们的货物
and you might rediscover the freedom which you so richly deserve.
然后你们就会发现自己完全应得的自由又回来了
i'm sure i don't need to remind you,but any of those who make the attempt to warn or turn themselves into the authority.
我想不用再多提醒了，但是如果有人尝试报警
we have the names and addresses of the families of everyone of you.
我们可是手握你们所有人家人的姓名和地址的哦
even the distant cousins.
甚至远房表亲也有哦
so we rely it for on your complete discretion.
我们的所做作为都基于你们慎重的考虑
good,anyway.gentlemen,madam,allow me to be the first to wish you
好了，无论如何，先生们，和这位小姐，请允许我先行祝贺你们
bon voyage!
一路平安！
ooops！
啊呀！
-are you gonna sell this? -i'm about to tell business model.
-你是打算卖这药？-要我说这是种商业模式
For primitive human beings like us,life seems to have only one,single purpose--gaining time.
对于我们这种落后的人类来说，生活似乎只有一个目的：挣得生存时间
and it is going through time seems to be also the only real purpose of [？] the cells  to our bodies
而我们体内的细胞也是如此
to achieve that end,the mass of the cells that make up earthworms and human beings has only two solutions.
为了达到目的，那些会组成蚯蚓或者人类的细胞只有两种解决方法
be immortal
永生不死……
or to reproduce
或者繁衍生息
If its habitat is not sufficiently favorable on nurturing
如果它处的环境不利于生长发育
the cell will choose immortality
细胞会选择不死
in other words,self sufficiency and self managemant
也就是说，它能自给自足、自我管理
on the other hand,if the habitat is favorable
另一方面，如果它处的环境有利于生长
they will choose to reproduce
它就选择繁衍生息
that way, when they die, they hand down essential information and  knowledge to the next cell.
选择这种方式的话，一旦它们死亡
which hands down to the next cell and so on
就会把必要的信息传递给繁衍出的细胞，如此这般一代一代传下去
thus,knowledge and Learning are handed down through time.
因此，知识和学习，都是通过时间传递的
ok,ok,keep calm,you've do which waste of time.
好好，保持冷静，你在浪费时间
any of time You can through the plane,just take the flank. Get out of here.It's the meanful thing right now.
穿过飞机，从侧翼出去，这是眼前最有意义的事情
just save time,don't try anything,keep your cool,
节约时间，别做其他，想办法冷静下来
you're alive  and others doesn't matter,just wait,save time.
只要活着一切都好，等待，节省时间……
save time
节省时间……
i'm not in the mood.
我没心情
Let's imagine for a few moments,what our life would be like,if we could access,let's say,20% of our brain capacity.
让我们设想一下
如果我们大脑的潜力能发挥出百分之二十，我们的生活会是怎样的
this freezed stage would give us access to and control of our own bodies.
达到这种程度，我们就可以了解和控制自己身体
-sir? -yes
-请问 -请讲
-Has it been proved scientificly? -Aw,for the moment,it's just a hypothesis,I confess.
-这有被科学地证明过吗？ -当下这只是个假说，我承认
but if you think about it,it's troubling to realize that the Greeks,Egyptians and the Indians had notion of cells centries before the invention of the microscope.
但是你再想想，在发明显微镜之前
几千年前伟大的古埃及人就有细胞的概念了，多令人费解
and what to say about Darwin whom everybody took him a fool when he put forward a theory of evolution
再来看达尔文。当年他提出进化论的时候，每个人都认为他是个傻子
it's up to us to push the rules&laws,and go from evolution to revolution
正是由我们决定去推动法律法规的发展，使进化变为革命
100 billion neurons for human
人类的一百亿个神经细胞
And just Only 15% are activiting
只有15%被发挥了出来
there are more connections in a human body than there are stars in the galaxy.
人体内的神经连接比银河里的星星都多
We possess a gigatic network of information to which we have almost no access.
我们都在体内拥有一个庞大的信息网络，而我们却无法发挥其所有的作用
-sir？-yes
-请问 -请讲
-And what would be the next stage? -well，the next stage would probably be the control of other people.
-那下一阶段会是什么呢？-嗯，下一阶段可能就是控制别人
but for that we will need to access at least 40% of our brain capacity.
但是为此我们就需要发挥出至少40%的大脑潜力
After control of our cells, and others, it comes control material.
在能控制我们自己和别人的细胞后，就来到了控制物质的阶段
But now we are rendering it to REMO sounds science fiction ...
但现在那就跟天方夜谭似的
and we don't know more than a dog who watches the moon.
我们对那个阶段还一无所知
-excuse me,sir! -Yes
-劳烦问个问题 -请讲
What will happen if,for some reason we ignored,somebody unlocked 100% of the role and capacity?
如果有人解锁了大脑百分之百的潜力
不管是如何做到的,会发生什么呢？
-100%? -Yes
-百分之百？ -是的
I have no idea.
我也不知道
-Hey! Do you speak English? -no no no
-嘿，你会说英语吗？ -不不不
-you speaks English? -Yes I am! -go to hospital now
-你会说英语吗？ -我会我会！-带老娘去医院
-Hospital. -Wait for me!
-医院到了  -给我等着
Miss, hello？hey，miss！
小姐，你干嘛呢？喂，小姐！
I need help.it's urgent!
我迫切需要你们的帮助
you cannot be in here,we're operating.please,get out.
你不能待在这里，我们正在做手术。请出去
It was impossible to save him anyway, the tumor invaded the cortex must be found
他已经抢救不回来了，肿瘤已经侵入了皮层
Something put a bag of drugs in me, I need you to remove it.
有人把毒品放到我的体内，我需要你把它取出来
-Do it now. -Right I‘ll  Just at a minutes I look around anesthesia you.
-现在就取. -好的，但是首先我要麻醉你
-Don't bother -Right
-不用了 -好吧
Ok, Calm down please, put the gun down.
好吧，请先镇静下来，把枪移走
I just come to, look something ,ok?
我要过来了，看看伤口状况，可以吗？
Do you mind? -No
-你介意我用吗？-不会的
-"Hello?" -Mom
-"你好" -妈
"Hey, Lucy, baby,it's great to hear from you.".
"嗨, Lucy, 亲爱的真高兴你打电话来"
"But What time is it over there?".
"现在那里几点了呀?".
-I don't know, it's night. - "Hold on a sec,let me get ride the other line.".
-我不知道，应该是晚上了. - "等我下，又有电话打过来了".
I'm gonna go down to go inside
我要深入做手术了
I'm back You are not partying too much,are  you, you promised me you look after yourself.
回来了，你没有参加太多派对，对吧？你答应我你会照顾好自己的
-I'm trying to Mom, I'm trying to
-我在努力去这样，老妈，我在努力
Well Thanks for calling  out of the blue like this. Your father gonna be sad that he missed you,he is out home for the Virginia.
好吧，你这次来电挺算出乎意料的惊喜，可惜你老爸不在家错过了这次通话
Usually you call me in the morning.- Mom -Yes -I feel everything
-你经常早上才打电话过来-妈 -嗯？-我感受到了一切
What do you mean, sweetie?
亲爱的你什么意思?
Space, air ...
空间，空气
the vibrations, the people ...
震动，人群
I can't feel the gravity ...
重力也不再是局限
I can feel the rotation of the earth ...
我能感受到地球的自转
the heat leaving my body.
我身体所丢掉的温度
The blood in my veins ...
我血管里流动的血液.
I can feel my brain.
我能感受到我的大脑思考
The depths parts of my memory.
记忆的最深处
"sweetie, we have a bad  connection，I can't hear you so well, what did you say about the memory?".
"亲爱的，信号不好，我听不清，你在讲什么，什么记忆?".
The pain in my mouth and the pain in my mouth when I had braces
我带牙齿矫正器时候嘴里的痛苦
I can remember the feeling of your hand on my forehead when I had a fever ...
我可以记起在我发烧时你摸在我额前的手掌
I remember the gentle cat is so soft. - "A cat，What cat, honey?".
我可以记起小猫是多么的柔软 - "小猫，亲爱的，什么猫?".
Siamese with blue eyes with broken tail.
蓝眼睛尾巴折了的暹罗猫
Sweetie you can't possible remember that, you are barely a year old
亲爱的你不可能记得那个，你那时还不到一岁
I remember the taste of your milk in my mouth ...
我还能记得母乳的味道
The room, the liquid   ...
那间房子，那些液体……
"Sweetie What do you talking about?".
"亲爱的你在讲什么啊?".
I just want to tell you I love you mum and dad.
我只想告诉您，妈，我爱您和老爸.
Sweetie.
亲爱的
And I want to Thank you for the thousand kisses that I can still feel on my face.
以及我想感谢您对我的数以千计的亲吻
-I love you mom. -I love you too, sweetie, more than anything in the world.
-老妈我爱你 -我也爱你，亲爱的，超越全世界的一切
-How much are the left? -500g.
-剩下的还有多少? -500克.
How long will take my body to remove the rest of it?
我的身体要多久才能吸收剩余的
To answer that,I did know what is this,may I? -Go ahead
去回答这个的话，我需要知道这些药是什么，可以么? -继续
CPH4.
Tell me about it
告诉我具体
pregnant women manufacture cph4 in the 6th week pregnancy
怀孕的女人在第六周的时候制造CPH4
For a baby, that has the power of an atomic bomb.
对于婴儿，这个威力相当于一颗原子弹
It must gives the fit for the necessary  energy for all the bombs in his body.
他必须要付出他的所有为了配合这颗原子弹
I’d heard they try to make a synthetic version of it，I didn't realize they were succeed
我只是知道他们要做一个综合版，但没想到他们成功了
If it really is CPH4,in this quantity ，I don't make you will just be alive
如果这确实是CPH4，而且用量这么多，我不知道你是怎么活下来的
Not for long.
不会太久了
Learnings are always painful process ,like like when you are little and your bones are growing and echo all over
学习总是一个痛苦的过程 ,就像在你小的时候你的骨骼在生长
can you believe I can remember the sound of my own bones growing ..
你能想象得到吗我还记得我骨头生长的声音
like the screaming under the skin.
就像皮肤深处在尖叫
Everything is different now,like the sounds and the music, I can  understand
现在的一切都不同了，就像声音和音乐，我能感受他们的内在
like flows
就像水流
It's funny I was used to be so corcern with who I was or what I wanna to be
我曾经一直我是谁或者我将会是谁，这点太有趣了
and now I've accessed the reach of my brain and I see things clearly and realize what  makes things ，us
而现在我能接收到我大脑所感知的一切
我对一切事、物,我们有了更深刻更清晰的理解和感悟
And it's primitive,they're obstacles.
这种感觉很原始，其他一切都似障碍
did that make any sense?
这样说你懂吗？
like this pain you are experiencing is blocking you from understanding
就像你现在所经历的痛苦，他在屏蔽你对其他事物的感知反应
all you know now is pain,it's all you know,pain
你所知道的一切只是痛苦，只是，痛苦
Where are the others, the others carry the drugs,I need the rest of it...
其他人都在哪里，其他身体里存放毒品的，我要知道他们的详细名单
for medicinal purposes
为了医学所用
Destination: Berlin.
Berlin.
柏林
Paris.
巴黎
Rome.
罗马
Thank you for sharing
谢谢你的分享
Oh evening  Professor(法语)
晚上好啊教授
-You have your full dinner tonight? -I'm afraid so
-您今晚有晚宴吗? -我恐怕是的
-I’m  exhausted -Have a good rest -Thank you.
-我已经筋疲力竭了 -好好休息哦 -谢谢
It's get shit out me ring?
滚远点别敲了
I missed you.
好想你呀
Me too.
我也是
-You lose your keys or something? -Yeah.
-你钥匙掉了还啥? -是的
Can I borrow your laptop? -Yeah,of course.
可以借用下你的笔电吗? -好啊，当然啦
So I had a hearing with the Chinese, awesome!
我之前去了个面试，太棒了
I sat here all day, they spoke in Chinese
就站一整天，不管会不会说中文
who understands the Chinese I don't understand the Chinese ...
谁会中文啊反正我不会
and then they said they always gonna call,because they won't do because they don't take your phone number, you know?
之前的人总说会打电话来，但肯定不会
因为他们根本就不问你要号码，好么？
Except this one guy, and he was not Chinese.
除了这个男人，他不是中国人哦
He works at the agency , and he's cute ...
他在这个中介工作，他可可爱了
OMG he's cute you know like the cute kinda way,the cute he does thing, OMG his ass
我的天，他做事都很可爱的，而且我的天他的屁股……
let me get started on that,and you never get sweet take me
我要和他开始了，你就再也刺激不到我了
4 seasons , royal sweets, honeymoon.
四季酒店皇家套房，做爱一整晚
I'm Sorry to talking about myself, what's up, how's  Richard?
真不好意思了我一直在讲自己，你呢，和Richard如何？
-He is dead.-You guys are so crazy.I will take a shower.
-他死了 -你们太疯狂了，我去洗个澡
-Yes. -Prof.Norman,my name's Lucy,I just read all your research about the human brain,we need to meet.
-你好
-诺曼教授您好，我叫lucy
刚刚阅读了您的所有关于人类大脑的研究课题，我想我们应该见个面
All of my research ?
我所有的研究课题？
Wow , I'm very flattered,but young lady,but I found it hard to believe.
额，我感到非常高兴，小姑娘，但是这让人难以相信
-That must be no less than...-6734 pages,I can recite all by heart if you wish.
-那至少有 -6734 页，我可以将它全部背出来如果您愿意听的话
Are you one of Emily's friends?It's sounds like one of the silly jokes.
你是Emily的朋友吗？这听起来就像一个笑话
-Is there she stay with you?-No,I'm alone.
-她和你在一起？ -不，就我一个人
-Who are you?-I just told you.
-你是谁？ -我刚才已经告诉过你了
Lucy? Right? Yes,sorry.
Lucy？是吗？抱歉
-I have read your theory about the use of the brains capacity,it's a little elementary,but you are on the right track.-Thank you.
-我已经读过了你关于使用脑容量的所有理论研究
虽然有点浅显，但你找到了正确的方向-谢谢
Prof. my cells are reproducing at a phenomenal speed,7 million/s.
我的细胞正以一种惊人的速度在生长着，达到了每秒七百万的速度
Now I'm having a trouble,in precisely evaluating the time of my death but in fact less than 24 hours
现在我有麻烦了
我不能准确的预估我的生命
我想我只剩下不到24个小时了
What are you talking about ?
你到底在说什么？
Well,I say that your theory is not a theory ,I absorbed  a large quantity of synthetic CPH4.
我想说的是你的理论不仅仅只是理论而已，我吸收了大量的CPH4
That was meant to make 100 percent  capacity
这意味着我的大脑性能能被百分之百的开发
Now,I'm at 28%,And  what you wrote is true ... once the brain reaches 20% and open up ...
我现在已经被开发了28%
如果你的理论是真实的，在20%之后大脑会被完全开发
Expanse the rest are no more obstacles and traps, they're following like  dominoes, I colonize my own brain.
那不是什么障碍或陷阱
这一切就像多米诺骨牌一样,我入侵了我自己的大脑
Well,I...I don't know what to say.
我不知道，该说什么
It's true,I have been work on this theory for 20 years.
我对这些理论研究了将近20年
But it's only I mean hypotheses, rasearch ideas.
它仅仅只是假设，是研究的假想
And I never thought anyone would ...
我从没想过真的会有人
-You can control all my metabolism?-Yes.
-你能控制我所有的新陈代谢活动？-是的
And I can start to control other people's bodies,also I can control magnets electric.
我可以控制别人的身体，也可以控制电流的磁场
well ,use them,not all of them,just some on the basic.TV
现在开始，请你看着屏幕 ，电视机
Telephone,radio
电话，收音机
It's amazing.
这简直太让人吃惊了
I don't feel pain.
我感觉不到疼痛
Fear.
恐惧
Desire.
欲望
It's like all things make a human fading away.
我的感知能力正在慢慢衰退
It's like to less human i feel...
这就好像……我的生理机能越来越弱
All these knowledge about everything quantum physics,a plenty of mathematics,
另一方面，好多知识，比如量子物理，数学等等
The infinite capacity and a cell nucleus .
还有无限增长的细胞核的能力
They are all exploding inside my brain all these knowledge.
所有的知识在我的脑海里急剧增长，现在我的脑子乱成一团
I don't know what to do with it.
现在这种情况，我不知道我该怎么办
If you're asking me what to do,
如果你问我该怎么做
You know, do you think about ?
你看，你有想过吗？
The vary nature of life ,I mean from the vary beginning.
生命的起源，它的本质
the development of the first cell divided into two cells.
是从第一个细胞分裂成两个然后开始发展开始的
The whole purpose of life is
生命的意义在于
pass on what we learned
传递我们的所学
There was no higher purpose.
除此之外没有别的了
And if you ask me what to do with all this knowledge you gain, I'd say.
如果你问我你该怎么处理你忽然得到的这些知识，我想说，
pass it on
传递下去
Just like any simple cell going through the time .
就像一个普通的细胞经历时间的考验，进化到现在一样
Time?
时间？
Yes,of course.
是的，当然
I'll be on your door in12 hours.
我会在12小时内去你家
-You are leaving?-Yes.
-你要走了？-是的
-What is this ?-a prescription
-这是什么？-一个药方
-Since when do you read Chinese?-Since a hour ago.
-你从什么时候起会中文的？-一个小时前
Lucy I don't understand any of this.
我看不懂，Lucy
Your kidneys and your function are not good, you need to make your lifestyle changes.
你的肾脏和肝脏不是很好，最好还是改变你的生活方式
Take this medication,work out,eat organic,you'll be ok.
好好吃药，多做运动，多吃有机食物，一切都会好起来的
- Del Rio-I just got a weird call from an American in Taiwan.
-Del Rio? -我收到了一个奇怪的电话，是一个住在台湾的美国人打的
A young woman says she details has a major drug trafficking.
一个年轻的女士说她手里掌握着一场重大毒品走私交易的细节消息
-Take the call- I will.
-我来接电话 -好的，我转给你
I have an important information about a group drug traffickers. I need to speak to someone have a positional authority.
我有关于那个走私交易的信息，我想和你们长官说话
auha,you are very lucky there is no one with more authority in this office than me.
啊哈，你很幸运，我就是办公室里那个最有权威的长官
Let's start the beginning.What's your name ?
我们开始吧。你叫什么？
Listen up,Del Rio,get off your desk,sitting on your chair,take up the red pen on your left,and write down what i say.
Del Rio，你听好了，从桌子上下来，坐到椅子上
拿起在你左边的红笔，把我所说的记下来
there are no cameras hurry up, I have no time to waste.
快点吧，那里没有监视器。我不能浪费任何时间
Go ahead.
- 继续
For getting be to sent me the details of three persons who about arriving up and each one have a kilo drugs.
给你三个即将着陆的人的资料，他们各携带一公斤毒品
I need you arrest them and collect the substance on it later.
你必须找到他们并且截获这些毒品
-What kind of drugs?-Powder.
-毒品是什么形态的？ -粉状的
-Hidden in pouch inside their intestines.-Excuse me ?
-他们将肠道开了个口子藏了进去 -什么？
You should be careful when you move to catch them,The product is very powerful.
你们行动的时候小心点，毒品的毒性非常强大
believe me ,got it ?-yeah.
-相信我，看到他们的照片了吗？ -看到了
Good. I'm counting on you.
好的，接下来就看你的了
Everything good?
你还好吗？
That's him.Hold him.
就是他！快抓住他！
请让让(法语。。)
Would you come with me.
先生，麻烦您跟我们来一下。没事，只是例行检查
看到了吗？
欢迎您来罗马，祝您旅途愉快（呆梨话。。。听不懂。。）
Sir, would you come with me.
请跟我们走一趟
- Yes, of course.
恩恩，好的
stop!
站住！
Del Rio!
这里是Del Rio
We stopped Kobelsky. -Thank you for calling me back.
-我们抓到一个 - 谢谢你回拨
I put it on hold.
我先把它放那儿
Thank you very much, we 'll see you couples hour at the transfer.
太感谢了，几个小时后我们在转机处见
That's it was three.
Ladies and gentlemen,we are now beginning on Paris Charles de Gaulle.
女士们先生们，我们将从巴黎戴高乐机场起飞
Miss, I have to ask you to put away your computers now. -Should wipe your nose.
-小姐，请合上你的电脑 -擦一下你的鼻子
Excuse me? -Made me a glass of champagne, please.
不好意思你再说一次？-给我杯香槟
Ah ... yes of course.
呃，好的没问题
Miss，your champagne.
小姐，你的香槟
Thank you.
谢谢
I'm very sorry,but you really need to close your table now. -Sure.
-抱歉，你现在必须关上你的小桌板 -是啊
To knowledge!
为了知识！
If its habitat is not quite officially favorable or naturally ...
如果它的所处的地方不是相对有利或者自然形成的
The cell will choose immortality.
细胞便会长生不老
In another word,self-sufficiency and self-management.
换句话来说，自给自足并且自我管理
You must stay seated!
你必须坐在位子上！
Open the door.We gonna land,so please open the door!
快开门！我们就要降落了，所以请你打开门！
Miss,miss ,please open the door!
小姐，请开门！
Do something!Help me.
做些什么！帮帮忙！
Last warn!Open the door!
这是最后一次警告了！快开门！
Miss,are you okay? Say something!
小姐，你还好吗?说句话啊！
Lucy, born March 10, 1988, Pennsylvania.
lucy，生于1988年3月10日，宾夕法尼亚
[French] She had scars? -Recent, there was still the son.
-她肚子上有疤？-是的还有线头
[French] How is she? -For now she sleeps.
-她怎么样了？ -现在在睡
With the sedative she is not ready to wake up.
她服用了镇定剂所以不会醒过来
[French]Doctor, she's awake! -Are you sure?
-医生，她醒了 -你确定？
Yes, she is sitting on her bed.
是的她坐在床上呢
[French] This is it. -You sure?
-你们不控制住她吗？ -我确定我们控制了
Yes.
Miss.
小姐
Do not move. -I need to talk to  you alone.
别动！-我想单独跟你聊聊
And l need you to put your hands up please!
我更想让你双手举过头顶！
Did you get the packets?
你拿到那几包东西了吗？
Yes.
拿到了
Where are they? -In a safe.
在哪？-在一个安全的地方
Here in Paris.
这儿，巴黎
It will be safer if in my hand.
在我手上更安全
[French]Don't leave the body here goes the park.
别把车停这，开停车场去
You know a cop who sees some pretty witched shit.
你知道吗，有个警察看到了超可怕的鬼东西
But I have to be honest with you,wish you would be there freak me out///
我老实告诉你，你在那把我吓死了
To put everybody to sleep like that,learning to be worried.
把所有人都搞睡着了，你能别老这么悠哉吗
I know.-good
我知道 -很好
Would you mind?
我开下收音机？
nope
没问题
What's that? -Korean, I'm gonna drive.
-那什么东西？-韩语，让我来开
Hey, no, no, no, this is a police car.
嘿，不，不，不，这是警车！
You can't ,no, this is not possible,lady,this is a police car!
你别，你不能这么做女士，这是辆警车!
[French] Well it is for us. -Here we go!
走吧伙计们
Sir,sir,excuse me sir,I need to talk to somebody! - [French] You see the police.
长官，长官，原谅我长官，我得找个人说话！- 警察来了
Look,I am a German citizen,and I demand a lawyer.
你看，我是个德国公民，我想找个律师
[French] I'll see in surgery. -Take us to eat.
-手术见 -给我带点吃的 -你可真能吃
You always drive like that?I've never driven before.
你经常这么开车吗？-我从没开过车
Great!
好极了！
Hey! That's one-way.-we are late.
嘿！这是单行道！-我们迟到了
Hey,I've never get ready in dead. -You never really die.
嘿，我还不想死 -你从来不会真的死掉
Sorry sir, I don't agree.
抱歉先生，我不太赞同
Agree, fine.
赞同，嗯
I'm gonna tell them to stop following us. -Don't bother.
-我要告诉他们别跟着我们了 -别忙活了
[French] Hey, I brought you a chicken ...
给你带了点培根
Give me the case.
把箱子给我
杀了她，把袋子拿来
别傻站着，杀了她！
Open it.
打开它
Let's go.
我们走
I'm not sure I could be really helpful to you.
我不太确定我能帮到你什么
yes you are. -What for?
-你有 -什么
My reminder ...-shall we go?
-带给我回忆 -我们可以出发了吗？
Where are we going? - [GPS Voice] "Take my first left.".
OK.
[French] No, no, off, let's go! Move!
跟上那辆车
-Professor? -Thank you.
-教授 -谢谢
-Hello? -Lucy.
-喂 -Lucy
-It’s her.Hey you,you are in Paris? -Yes I am.
-是她 你现在在巴黎吗 –嗯
Good, good, excellent!
好 太好了
So,look,I am no longer at the hotel now, I’ve come to the university
我现在不在宾馆去大学了
[?]We have taken the liberty of calling together a few of  my colleagues to discuss your case.Top minds In their field
我把我们领域最好的同事都叫上了来解决你的问题
And they are very trustfully. -I trust you.
-他们都值得信任 –我相信你
Thank you.So do you think you can can make it to the university?
-谢谢 你能来趟大学吗
-I’m..I’m very pleased to meet you. -Likewise.
-很高兴见到你 –我也是
-Captain Del Rio. –How do you do.
-Del Rio警长 –你还好吗
Let me introduce you to my colleagues.
介绍一下我的同事
-This is Professor Cartier Neurosurgeon. -I know who everyone is.
-这是卡迪尔教授 –这里的每个人我都认识
Of course.
当然
Gentlemen, this is Lucy, the first woman to...I mean
绅士们 这是Lucy 她是第一个 我是说
As I mentioned earlier，Miss Lucy has for reasons that made a mystery to me
我之前提到过她，Lucy小姐对我来说是个传奇
Unlocked certain portions of her brain that offer access to previously unexplored 3 ? zones
破解了她脑中人类尚未探索的区域
She has abilities ...
她有特殊的能力
Can you give us an example?
你能举个例子吗
Your daughter Gabriel,age 6died in a car accident.
你的女儿六年前死于车祸
It was a blue car ()butter seats, a palstic bird hanging from the rearview mirror.
那是一辆蓝色的车,一只塑料鸟玩具挡住了后视镜
老板，我们五个人在医院被撂倒了，对不起
还剩多少人？
我还有25个人跟着
那个小婊子她不肯屈服
她就是个女巫
我懂
我会亲手杀了她的
There are men coming here, can you secuiry the room, I need to stay focused. -Sure.
有人来了 保护我 我需要集中注意力  -好的
快点
How did you manage to access all these information?
你是怎么成功获取那么多信息的
Electrical inpulses every cell knows and talks to every other cell.It exchange  1000s Bits of information between them per sec.
电脉冲以每秒1000B的速度在每个细胞之间交换传递信息
Cells grouped together forming a giant web of communication
细胞群组成了一张巨大的信息网
Which interns forms matter
用来转换物质
Cells get together,take on one form,de-form,re-form.Takes no difference,it’s all the same.
细胞聚在一起 同时转变成各种形态
Humans consider themselves unique, so they built their whole theory  existence on their uniquness.
人类自认为独特 认识他们是无与伦比的
One is the unit of measurement, but it is not
其中最为独特的是他们的测量系统 但其实不是
All social system we put into place are mere sketches 1 +1 = 2.That’s all we’ve learnt.
你们只承认一加一等于二的社会系统
But one plus one has never equal 2.
但一加一从不等于二
There are in fact no numbers and no letters we couldn’t find our systems to bring it down to human sides to make it comprehenceble
其实人类创造的数字并不被宇宙外界所认可
We’ve created the scales that we can
我们有自己心中的那把秤
forget its unfathomable scale.
忘记你们的那杆秤吧
But if humans are not the unit of measurement ...
但如果人类不用这套测量准则
And the world isn’t governed by mathematical laws ...
世界就不会被数字法则统治了
What governs all of them?
是什么统治了他们
Former cars speeding down the road, speed of the image infinitly
这辆车持续加速到无限后
And the car disappears.
就会消失
So what  proof do we have of its existence?
所以有什么能证明它存在过
Time gives the ????? to existence, time is the only true unit of measure.
时间是存在的原因 时间是宇宙中的唯一真理
It gives proof to the existence of matter
它为事物提供存在过的证据
Without time, we don’t exist.
没有时间 我们将不复存在
Time is unity.
时间是宇宙的统一体
给我搜索整栋楼找她
You won’t able to hold’em for much long.
坚持不了多久了
Time to go, then.
快开始吧那
Are you sure you need such huge doses?I’m afraid you won’t survive.
你确定要注射这么大剂量吗 你可能活不成了
Some thousands cells inside me will fight and defend their integrity until to the very end.
我的细胞会抵抗并保持完好无损
In order to attain the last percent I have to force it.
为了完全开发大脑，我必须逼自己
To crap the cells open to their nuclears.
才能使细胞打开核心
All this knowledge, Lucy ...
所有这些知识 Lucy
I’m not even sure that mankind is ready for it, we are so driven by power profit.
我不确定人类是否已经准备好接受了 我们总是被利益驱使
Given man's nature
改造自然
It might bring us only instability and chaos.
或许会给我们带来战争和混乱
Ignorance brings chaos, not knowledge ...
无知才会带来混乱 知识不会
I will built a computer and download my knowledge, and I’ll find a way for you access to it.
我会建一个电脑上传我的知识 然后给你登入的权限
I just hope we will be worthy of your sacrifice.
希望你的牺牲不会白费
Nobody move!
不准动
Do you understand English?
听得懂英语吗
-what she’s doing? –She’s looking for energy and matter.
-她在干什么 –她在寻找能量和物质
And she’s trying to connect the analogue computer.
并且试图连接计算机
崇鸡啊！
我在这老大
干点什么啊喂
是！老大
你们，过来
准备好没？
[French] (whispered) ... fast!
你怎么样？ 准备急救
Oh my god ... what happening?
天呐 发生了什么
What is it making?
她在干嘛
New generation computer computer of hers own.
属于她的新一代电脑诞生了
她去哪儿了？！
回答我！
Hey! You!
嘿 你
Look,The computer,it is moving move!
电脑在动
Where she is?
她在哪儿
"I am everywhere."
我无处不在
Life was given to us a million years ago.
我们的生命起源于十亿年前
Now you know what to do with it!
现在你总该知道应该用它做什么了吧